<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | PKMS Lab | UBC</title>
    <link>https://a2mahara.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a2mahara.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a2mahara.github.io/images/icon_hu254a632e13bbcb0db1c9ac000befa917_11344_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://a2mahara.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>US FDA revokes emergency use authorization of hydroxychloroquine for treatment of COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://a2mahara.github.io/post/dec4_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2mahara.github.io/post/dec4_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The result of our study published in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapediatrics/fullarticle/2767020&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;JAMA Pediatrics&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was used to support the US FDA&amp;rsquo;s decision to revoke emergency use authorization of hydroxychloroquine for treatment of COVID-19. Our model-based analysis demonstrated that hydroxychloroquine concentrations in lung tissue may be too low to elicit an antiviral effect - raising concerns about use of hydroxychloroquine for treatment of COVID-19. This work epitomizes the impact that pharmacokinetic modeling and simulation can have on clinical care. The FDA communication can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fda.gov/media/138945/download&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New, New, New</title>
      <link>https://a2mahara.github.io/post/dec3_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2mahara.github.io/post/dec3_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of new beginnings this year. Relocated to a new city - the strikingly beautiful Vancouver, British Columbia. Appointed as a new Assistant Professor at The University of British Columbia&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences. Launched a new laboratory website. And now, I am looking to recruit inaugural members to the PKMS laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are creative, enjoy biology, pharmacology and math, and are enthusiastic about conducting research that can impact clinical care, then consider submitting an application. As a lab member in the newly formed PKMS lab, you will play a critical role in shaping this laboratory’s research and culture. Click &lt;a href=&#34;../../join/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to find more information on currently available positions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
