<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Cohen-Wolkowiez | PKMS Lab | UBC</title>
    <link>https://pkms.ca/author/michael-cohen-wolkowiez/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pkms.ca/author/michael-cohen-wolkowiez/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Michael Cohen-Wolkowiez</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pkms.ca/images/icon_hu254a632e13bbcb0db1c9ac000befa917_11344_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Michael Cohen-Wolkowiez</title>
      <link>https://pkms.ca/author/michael-cohen-wolkowiez/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulated Assessment of Pharmacokinetically Guided Dosing for Investigational Treatments of Pediatric Patients With Coronavirus Disease 2019</title>
      <link>https://pkms.ca/publication/hcq_jama/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pkms.ca/publication/hcq_jama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our model-based analysis, published in &lt;em&gt;JAMA Pediatrics&lt;/em&gt;, sought to identify pediatric dosages for two expirimental COVID-19 therapies (hydroxychloroquine and remdesivir). A combination of PBPK modeling and allometry was used to define pediatric dosages for different development stages. Interestingly, our PBPK model analysis indicated that hydroxychloroquine lung concentrations would fall well below those needed to illicit an antiviral effect, raising concerns of its effectiveness for COVID-19 treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Maharaj, A. R., Wu, H., Hornik, C. P., Balevic, S. J., Hornik, C. D., Smith, P. B., Gonzalez, D., Zimmerman, K. O., Benjamin, D. K., Jr, &amp;amp; Cohen-Wolkowiez, M. (2020). Simulated Assessment of Pharmacokinetically Guided Dosing for Investigational Treatments of Pediatric Patients With Coronavirus Disease 2019. &lt;em&gt;JAMA Pediatrics&lt;/em&gt;, 174(10), e202422. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.2422&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.2422&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population pharmacokinetics of olanzapine in children</title>
      <link>https://pkms.ca/publication/olanzapine_bjcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pkms.ca/publication/olanzapine_bjcp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We described the population pharmacokinetics of olanzapine in a cohort of 45 children. Olanzapine is an atypical antipsychotic indicated for treatment schizophrenia and bipolar I disorder but is commonly prescribed off-label to treat delirium and agitation in critical care settings. Our analysis represents the first of its kind to describe the pharmacokinetics of olanzapine in children ranging from infants to adolescents. Olanzapine’s half-life was found to exhibit a U-shaped pattern across the developmental age range. Simulations from our final model were used to propose a preliminary dosing strategy for children. Our developed dosing scheme used weight‐normalized doses for children ≤6 months postnatal age or &amp;lt;15 kg and fixed doses for children ≥15 kg. The manuscript was published in the &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Maharaj, A. R., Wu, H., Zimmerman, K. O., Autmizguine, J., Kalra, R., Al-Uzri, A., Sherwin, C. M. T., Goldstein, S. L., Watt, K., Erinjeri, J., Payne, E. H., Cohen-Wolkowiez, M., &amp;amp; Hornik, C. P. (2020). Population pharmacokinetics of olanzapine in children. &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/bcp.14414&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/bcp.14414&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
